James Rutkowski

1939 Balmoral Dr.
Brighton, MI 48114
(810) 772-3801
j.r.rutkowski52@gmail.com

To whom it may concern,

After graduating college, the first type of job I wanted was one that would allow me to use Japanese on a daily basis. I found that by working for the Japanese Government, mostly as a chauffeur, for many years. And for a while it was new and interesting and provided me with opportunities for personal growth, but after many years I started to feel stagnated. I started to consider a career pivot. I took a coding bootcamp and for a while, it just felt like a means to an end. Just a way towards a potential new job.

However, it no longer feels like that anymore. After finishing my bootcamp, I have slowly but surely gained a passion for programming and it feels like for the first time in my life I have a clear path forward that I would like to take. For a while now I have just been gaining a breadth of knowledge. Outside of the bootcamp I took, I have some knowledge of Python, some of PHP, a basic understanding of some algorithms, and a little bit of R. But now I am aiming more for depth and understanding in a single tech-stack and that is where my studies currently find me. I am ready to leverage the knowledge I have gained to help your company meet your goals which will, in turn, help me realize my own in a mutually beneficial partnership.

I very much appreciate having the opportunity to apply for this position and am very much looking forward to any opportunity that may be provided to me.

Sincerely,

James Rutkowski

James Rutkowski

1939 Balmoral Dr. Brighton, MI 48114 (810) 772-3801 j.r.rutkowski52@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I want to be an asset for your company using the skills that I gained from my recent studies in programming while furthering my knowledge in whatever technologies the job requires me to use both on and off the job.. I also hope to learn a great deal from the more experienced professionals I will be working with.

EDUCATION

Coursera

February 2022 - Present

- Completed Google Data Analytics Certificate
- Completed Python for Everybody Specialization

Career Foundry

February 2021 - September 2021

• Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development.

Eastern Michigan University | Ypsilanti, MI

June 2011 - May 2015

• BS in Mathematics, Japanese Language & Culture, and English Linguistics.

EXPERIENCE

Consulate General of Japan in Detroit | Chauffeur

February 2016 - December 2021 - Detroit, MI

- Trusted to drive the Consul General and any VIPs that visited, such as ambassadors or royalty.
- Kept up to date on construction and traffic patterns to assure that the Consul General is on time to appointments.

Consulate General of Japan in Detroit | Butler / Maintenance

October 2015 - January 2016 - Detroit, MI

- Served guests and managed additional staff at official dinners and receptions held at the Consul General's residence.
- Kept the grounds and residence maintained and alerted consulate staff of any problems that arise.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JS, Git, and React framework
- Node.js, PHP, SQL
- Additional knowledge in Python and R
- Microsoft Office or Google equivalent
- Problem Solving
- Analytical
- Desire to Learn

AWARDS

Hilton G Falahee Scholarship for Mathematics - Eastern Michigan University - 2014

Michigan Japanese Language Speech Contest Winner - 2015

LANGUAGES

English - Native

Japanese - Conversational

PORTFOLIO

https://boundforearth.github.i o/My-Portfolio-Website/inde x.html